A Guide to the Randolph Family Papers, 1783-1909, 1791-1909
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Mary [?] to Margaret Randolph, 1837 April 14, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with address; postmarked Tallahassee, FL, April 17. (Box-folder 1:57)
  Concerning "Papa's long attack," Willie's "spell," and the near completion of their Church. She later states, "I saw in a late paper that Cousin [Thomas] Jeff[erson Randolph] had received an appointment & also that he had declined it," and asks whether several of her letters have been received by family members.
- George Wythe Randolph to Margaret Smith Randolph, 1837 May 13, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; postmarked Portsmouth, VA, May 16. (Box-folder 1:58)
  Concerning his upcoming examination for the military, declining cotton prices, and economic trouble for members of his family. He continues, "what a terrible state the country is in. Every body failing. To day we received word that all the banks to the northward have stopped paying specie, and the banks here [in Portsmouth] have done the same."
- Thomas Mann Randolph Bankhead to Margaret Smith Randolph, 1837 December 6, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso; Barrow. (Box-folder 1:59)
  Concerning the death of her Uncle [Meriwether] Lewis [Randolph], and claims that his death will not alter his intention to move to Arkansas.
- Nicholas P. Trist to Margaret Smith Randolph, 1838 January 9, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf. (Box-folder 1:60)
  Concerning a gift of a barrel of oranges, and their recent family loss.
- Mary [?] to Margaret Smith Randolph, 1838 February 2, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso; with wax seal; Barrow. (Box-folder 1:61)
  Concerning her father's improving health, and several deaths of acquaintances, with religious consolation for the same.
- James [?] to Margaret Smith Randolph, 1838 March 8, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf. (Box-folder 1:62)
  Relating that he will soon be leaving for New Orleans, and apologizing for not having seen more of her during his time at port.
- J. S. S. to Margaret Smith Randolph, 1838 March 16, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso; with wax seal; postmarked "L. Donaldson." (Box-folder 1:63)
  A note from her physician expressing his joy at her recovered health, and requesting that she and her children visit him.
- Francis Wayles Eppes to Thomas Jefferson Randolph, 1841 January 14, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso; docketed; postmarked Tallahassee, FL, January 1. (Box-folder 1:64)
  Concerning a theological dispute between them, and claiming that Thomas Jefferson Randolph is nearly an atheist. Francis mentions two controversial religious figures from the period, and after reprimanding Thomas for his views says, "But I do not mean to defend the individuals to whom I plainly understand you to allude. The papers of Dr. Tyng in the Recorder and Dr. [Francis] Hawks in the New York Review are condemned by every Minister of the Gospel that I have heard speak on the subject. Assuredly they will meet their reward. But shld the cruelty & injustice of two men, or of a hundred wolves in sheepsclothing, set you against the whole Church of Christ."
- William H. Roane to Thomas Jefferson Randolph, 1841 July 28, ALS, 1 p.; docketed. (Box-folder 1:65)
  A letter of introduction and recommendation for Mr. J. Guillet for his application for the professorship of Modern Languages at the University [of Virginia].
- Thomas Jefferson Randolph to "Dear Mother," 1843 April 10, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:66)
  Containing his report card for March 1842, on the same sheet as his letter to his mother concerning life at school.
- Jane Hollins Randolph to Thomas Jefferson Randolph, [1843?] Wednesday 22, AL transcript, 4 pp. on 4 l. (Box-folder 1:67)
  Lamenting their separation, claiming that on a visit she was happy not to have had to speak with Archy Cary, and that she does not care ever to see him again. Providing advice on handling when "dear Maria" could think about an engagement.
- Thomas Randolph to "Dear Sir," 1850 August 3, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:68)
  Regarding Thomas Jefferson's papers, their arrangement, and housing.
- Edwin Wortham to Thomas Jefferson Randolph, 1852 April 9, ALS, 1 p.; with attached address leaf; docketed; postmarked Richmond, VA, April 10, and Charlottesville, VA, April 11; Barrow. (Box-folder 1:69)
  A bill of sale for blasting powder, and fuse.
- Thomas Jefferson Randolph, Jr. to [Unidentified], 1853 June 19, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:70)
  Concerning preparations for his arrival at Edge Hill.
- "Mother" to [Unidentified], 1855 November 20, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:71)
  Sending money, concerning a lawsuit, and relating other family matters.
- Carey Randolph to Sarah Randolph, 1862 June 9, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with envelope; Barrow. (Box-folder 1:72)
- Jno. Turner to F. W. Page, 186[2] October 3, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:73)
- R. G. H. Kean to Mary B. Randolph, 1862 November 17, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. (Box-folder 1:74)
- Envelope addressed to T[homas] J[efferson] Randolph, [ca. 1863-1865], 1 item. (Box-folder 1:75)
- Note re shipments of hay "For Captain Tutwiler," [ca. 1863-1865], AN, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:76)
- William E. Royall to Thomas Jefferson Randolph, 1863 June 26, ALS, 1 p. (Box-folder 1:77)
- W. W. Cosby to Thomas Jefferson Randolph, 1863 August 28, ALS, 1 p.; with address on verso; docketed. (Box-folder 1:78)
- Jno. C. Turner to Thomas Jefferson Randolph, 1863 September 5, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf; docketed; Barrow. (Box-folder 1:79)
- William E. Royall to Thomas Jefferson Randolph, 1863 September 7, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. (Box-folder 1:80)
- W. S. Fontaine to Thomas Jefferson Randolph, 1863 September 10, ALS, 1 p.; with address on verso; docketed. (Box-folder 1:81)
- W. W. Cosby to Thomas Jefferson Randolph, 1863 September 30, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with address; docketed; postmarked Powhatan, VA, October 3. (Box-folder 1:82)
- J. J. Hopkins to [Thomas Jefferson] Randolph, 1863 October 6, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; docketed. (Box-folder 1:83)
- Alex M. Trabny to Thomas Jefferson Randolph, Jr., 1863 October 17, ALS, 1 p.; with address on verso; docketed. (Box-folder 1:84)
- W. W. Cosby to Thomas Jefferson Randolph, Jr., 1863 November 4, ALS, 1 p.; with address on verso; docketed. (Box-folder 1:85)
- W. W. Cosby to Thomas Jefferson Randolph, 1863 November 7, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso. (Box-folder 1:86)
- William S. Early to T. J. Hopkins, 1863 November 11, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:87)
- R. B. Trent to Thomas Jefferson Randolph, 1863 December 12, ALS, 1 p.; with address on verso; docketed. (Box-folder 1:88)
- Confederate States Invoices for Supplies, Major Thomas Jefferson Randolph, Quartermaster, 1864, ANsS, 11 items. (Box-folder 1:89)
- W. W. Cosby to Tho[ma]s J[efferson] Randolph, Jr., 1864 February 13, ALS, 1 p.; address on verso; docketed. (Box-folder 1:90)
- John [Noad]? to J. Briggs, 1864 March 17, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:91)
- H. Harris to [Unidentified], 1864 March 28, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:92)
- Thomas C. Bigger receipt for hay, 1864 June 22, ADS, 1 p. (Box-folder 1:93)
- W. W. Cosby to T[homas] J[efferson] Randolph, Jr., 1864 July 30 and 1864 December 30, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:94)
  Possibly from copybook. Letter in disrepair and difficult to read.
- A. R. Lawtone (?) to T[homas] J[efferson] Randolph, Jr., 1864 August 9, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:95)
- J. J. Hopkins to [Thomas Jefferson] Randolph, Jr., 1864 August 22, ALS, 1 p.; with address on verso; docketed; postmarked Howardsville, VA, August 23. (Box-folder 1:96)
- W. S. Fontaine to F. W. Puge, 1864 September 17, ALS, 1 p.; with address on verso. (Box-folder 1:97)
- [Brauck]? to R. H. Stratton, 1864 September 28, ALS, 1 p.; with address on verso. (Box-folder 1:98)
  With additional letter written 1864 September 30 by R. H. Stratton to "Dear Sir." With enclosure.
- J. J. Allen to [Unidentified], 1864 October 11, ALS, 1 p. (Box-folder 1:99)
- Thomas Jefferson Randolph to C. S. Canington, 1864 October 15, ALS, 1 p.; docketed. (Box-folder 1:100)
- J. J. Allen to Thomas Jefferson Randolph, 1864 November 18, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:101)
- [Johnston]? to Captain C. H. Locker, 1864 November 23, ADS, 1 p. (Box-folder 1:102)
  Endorsed on verso.
- Wm. M. Jones and others to T[homas] J[efferson] Randolph, Jr., 1864 November 28, ALS, 1 p. (Box-folder 1:103)
- W. W. Cosby to Thomas Jefferson Randolph, Jr., 1865 March 1, ALS, 1 p. (Box-folder 1:104)
- [Agnes Dillon Randolph] to Maurie, 1865 June 25, AL fragment, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:105)
- Ellen Wayles Randolph Coolidge to Carolina Randolph, 1866 August 17, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with envelope; postmarked Paris, August 17. (Box-folder 1:106)
- [Ellen Wayles Randolph Coolidge] to [Carolina Randolph], 1867 January 21, AL fragment, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:107)
- Ellen Wayles Randolph Coolidge to Jane Hollins Nicholas Randolph, 1867 April 29, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:108)
  Concerning George Wythe Randolph.
- [Agnes Dillon Randolph] to [Unidentified], [1867?] October 30, AL fragment, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:109)
- V.[irginia] J.[efferson] T.[rist] to Mary [Jefferson Randolph], 1868 September 1, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:110)
- Agnes [Dillon Randolph] to "Dearest Brother," 1870 December 7, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:111)
- Obituaries for Jane Hollins Randolph and M. Lewis Randolph, [ca. 1871 February], D, 1 p. (Box-folder 1:112)
- Sarah Randolph to G. W. Randolph, 1872 August 15, ALS, 26 pp. on 7 l. (Box-folder 1:113)
  Re death of Thomas Jefferson Randolph, Jr.
- Agnes D[illon] R[andolph] to "My Dear Brother," 1872 August 28, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. (Box-folder 1:114)
- Agnes [Dillon Randolph] to Cluskey, 1875 December 8, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:115)
- Ag[nes Dillon Randolph] to [Mamie], 1877 February 19, ALS, 8 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:116)
- T[homas] J[efferson] Randolph to Mary, 1880 February 15, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 1:117)
- "Jeff" to "Mary," 1883 June 14, ALS, 3 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 1:118)
- T. E. Everett[?] to [Sarah N.] Randolph, 1884 February 6, ALS, 1 p. (Box-folder 2:1)
  Concerning Robert E. Lee monument.
- Sally Carter to Mary Randolph, 1884 October 2, ALS fragment, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with envelope; with enclosure; postmarked Catonsville, MD, 1884 October 2. (Box-folder 2:2)
- P[aul] Otto to Sarah N. Randolph, 1884 December 11, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:3)
- Paul Otto to Sarah N. Randolph, 1885 June 2, ALS, 1 p. (Box-folder 2:4)
- Paul Otto to Sarah N. Randolph, 1885 December 16, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:5)
- P[aul] Otto to Sarah N. Randolph, 1886 March 26, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:6)
- P[aul] Otto to Sarah N. Randolph, 1886 April 7, ALS, 5 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:7)
- F[rank] Otto Schulze to Paul Otto, 1886 April 7, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:8)
- P[aul] Otto to Sarah N. Randolph, 1886 April 19, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:9)
- P[aul] Otto to Sarah N. Randolph, 1886 July 15, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:10)
- F[rank] Otto Schulze to Sarah N. Randolph, 1886 July 18, ALS, 15 pp. on 4 l. (Box-folder 2:11)
  Concerning Robert E. Lee memorial.
- F[rank] Otto Schulze to Sarah N. Randolph, 1886 [August 1]?, ALS, 6 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:12)
- P[aul] Otto to Sarah N. Randolph, 1886 September 30, ALS, 10 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 2:13)
- P[aul] Otto to Sarah N. Randolph, 1886 October 26, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:14)
- F[rank] Otto Schulze to Sarah N. Randolph, 1887 April-, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:15)
- [Mamie] to Agnes [Dillon Randolph], 1894 March 20, ALS, 8 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:16)
- [Mamie] to "My dearly beloved and badly-treated niece," [Agnes Dillon Randolph], 1894 June 6, ALS, 32 pp. on 8 l. (Box-folder 2:17)
- Printed "List of Jefferson... Papers.. .," [ante 1898], 1 p. (Box-folder 2:18)
- [Agnes] Dillon [Randolph] to Joe, 1909 September 1, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:19)
- Mary [?] to Margaret Randolph, n.y. February 16, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso; postmarked Winchester, VA, February 16; Barrow. (Box-folder 2:20)
- Septimia [Randolph] to Margaret Randolph, n.y. February 24, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with address; postmarked City of Washington, March 3. (Box-folder 2:21)
- M. N[icholas] to Mrs. Thomas Jefferson Randolph, n.y. April 15, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with address; postmarked Baltimore, MD, April 15; Barrow. (Box-folder 2:22)
- [Agnes Dillon Randolph] to "My Dear Madam," n.y. April 24, AL, 12 pp. on 3 l. (Box-folder 2:23)
- Mary [?] to "The Misses Randolph," n.y. June 2, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with address; Barrow. (Box-folder 2:24)
- Mary [?] to Margaret Randolph, n.y. June 13, ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; Barrow. (Box-folder 2:25)
- M[ary] P[age] R[andolph] to Margaret Randolph, n.y. June 16 "Sunday Evening", ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf. With partial wax seal. (Box-folder 2:26)
- Agnes [Dillon Randolph] to [Mamie], n.y. June 19, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:27)
- A[gnes] D[illon] R[andolph] to [Mamie], n.y. October 14, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:28)
- A[gnes] D[illon] Randolph to her "cousin" Cluskey, n.y. November 18, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:29)
- [Unidentified] to [Unidentified], n.y. December 11, AN, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:30)
  Concerning the movement of property. Mentions disposing of Jefferson works "to the best advantage."
- M. M. S[mith]? To Miss Margaret Randolph, n.d. Sunday, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with address; Barrow. (Box-folder 2:31)
- [Unidentified] to Peggy [Margaret] Randolph, n.d. Thursday Morning, ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with address. (Box-folder 2:32)
- J. H. K. to Th[omas] J[efferson] Randolph, n. y. -22, ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with address; Barrow. (Box-folder 2:33)
- [Agnes Dillon Randolph] to Unidentified, n. d., AL fragment, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:34)
- L. A. M. to Margaret Randolph, n. d., ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:35)
- L. W. to "Mag" [Margaret Randolph], n. d., ALS, 1 p. (Box-folder 2:36)
- Ag[nes Dillon Randolph] to "her cousin," n. d., ALS, 8 pp. on 2 l. (Box-folder 2:37)
- Agnes Dillon Randolph's "In Memoriam. Margaret in her sixth year," n.d., AMsS, 5 pp. on 5 l. (Box-folder 2:38)
- [Agnes Dillon Randolph] to [Unidentified], n.d., AL fragment, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:39)
- [Agnes Dillon Randolph] to [Unidentified], n. d., AL fragment, 4 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:40)
- T[homas] J[efferson] Randolph's reminiscences of Jane H. Nicholas Randolph, n. d., AMsS, 8 pp. on 2 l. In unidentified hand. (Box-folder 2:41)
- Thomas Jefferson Randolph to Mary, n. d., ALS, 1 p. (Box-folder 2:42)
- Mary [?] to Margaret Randolph, n. d., ALS, 3 pp. on 1 l.; with address on verso. (Box-folder 2:43)
- E[llen] W. H[arrison] to Margaret S. Carter, n.d., TL, 1 p.; Barrow. (Box-folder 2:44)
- Sept[ima] Antoinette Christine Constance to Miss Margaret Randolph, n. d., ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with address; Barrow. (Box-folder 2:45)
- Margaret M. Smith to "Dear Meg," n. d., ALS, 4 pp. on 1 l.; with address; Barrow. (Box-folder 2:46)
- Elizabeth M. Bankhead to Margaret Smith Randolph, n. d., ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf. (Box-folder 2:47)
- E[lizabeth] M. B[ankhead] to [Margaret Smith Randolph], n .d., ALS, 2 pp. on 1 l. (Box-folder 2:48)
- [Elizabeth M. Bankhead] to Margaret Smith Randolph, n. d., AL fragment, 2 pp. on 1 l.; with attached address leaf. (Box-folder 2:49)